☐ 615-668-4657

igustinav38@gmail.com

github.com/justinavickers

linkedin.com/in/justina-vickers

JUSTINA VICKERS

Software Developer

ABOUT ME

As a natural problem solver, I have yearned for a career with room to grow and the possibilities are endless. On a recommendation from my family, I started doing some research and worked on tutorials from CodeCademy and Udemy. Everything I learned about software made it the obvious choice. I joined the Jumpstart program at NSS, and fell in love. I then applied and was accepted into the 6-month course! I am lucky to have the opportunity to continually learn and grow with this career. The challenges motivate me to expand my knowledge, feed my creativity, and desire to become a better developer.

PROJECTS

Trail Boxes: Front-End Capstone

https://github.com/justinavickers/Trail-Boxes https://trail-boxes.herokuapp.com/

As an aspiring Appalachian Trail thru hiker, I found there aren't any good platforms to organize your drop boxes for a several month journey. We have spreadsheets but those can get easily disorganized and can become confusing. With Trail Boxes, the user can organize and display all boxes being prepped.

- Single page React web app utilizing JavaScript, React, Reactstrap, and asynchronous fetch calls with a JSON API.
- Google Maps API for map feature with the post office markers.

Inhale: Back-End Capstone

https://github.com/justinavickers/Inhale

I am an avid user of essential oils and I always have a hard time remembering recipes that I like to use that I have made. This app allows users to share and save those recipes. Another problem I wanted to solve was to have a platform allowing users to learn how use those specific oils in recipes by providing the benefits and uses for each oil.

 Inhale is a c#/ ASP.NET web application built using entity and identity framework.

ACADEMIC BACKGROUND

Nashville Software School, 2019

EXPERIENCE

Nashville Software School: Junior Full-Stack Developer 2018-2019 6-month full-time immersive full-time web development bootcamp.

- Created single page applications in Javascript using React.js framework, CSS3 and Bootstrap
- Worked with the jQuery Javascript library for DOM manipulation
- Utilized Grunt to automate bundling of modules and JavaScript linting
- Project management/tracking with GitHub Issue Tracking
- Experience building c#/ ASP.NET web applications using Entity and Identity framework
- Built SQL queries using Azure Data Studio, SSMS, as well as within applications using ADO.NET

Group Projects

- Single page application for a user to chat with friends, add tasks and save articles.
- Single page application for tourists coming to Nashville. The user can make an itinerary for a park, meetup, concert or restaurant they want to visit. This was accomplished by accessing data through four external API's using asynchronous fetch calls in JavaScript. Using this data, search results are dynamically displayed on the DOM.

Jimmy Johns: General Manager

2014-2017

- Managed a team of 30 people including part-time and full-time employees
- Performed all manager duties for staff including hiring, terminations, onboarding and performance reviews
- Used team building exercises to promote a sense of cohesiveness among the staff
- Managed all inventory, budgeting, and overhead costs
- Trained and audited all staff members
- Held regular sit downs with managers to discuss the implementation of personal improvement plans for the purpose of bettering overall morale and confidence

Twinkleen: Co-Owner

2011-2014

Residential and Commercial Environmentally-friendly cleaning business

- Responsible for creating company website using Go Daddy
- Managed customer relationships including face to face sales consultation, company wide scheduling, and client focused quality control check-ins
- In charge of hiring, firing, and training of all employees
- Month to month sales profited organization \$3000 on average after business expenses and payroll
- Utilized Facebook Marketing as our main marketing source but gathered most clientele through word of mouth
- Worked on partnering arrangements with other local green businesses
- Retained 95% our clients for the full term of our business